



lizfaria.com 🁋 efaria93@gmail.com

ABOUT

Hi, my name's Liz and I'm a full stack developer based in Toronto who specializes in JavaScript. I have 6 years experience building high quality enterprise applications on agile teams in entrepreneurship, banking, restaurant and agency industries. I want to be part of expanding possibilities by collaborating across teams to solve problems and help build an outstanding product that has a positive impact on users' lives.

EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Ownr | RBCx, April 2020 - Present

Typescript, React, Node, NestJs, PostgreSQL, Jest, Puppeteer, Copilot, Github Actions

- develop the core application to collect user data and build automations to access bank and government sites to create and update companies for users, as well as generate legal documentation
- led migration of legacy custom identity flow to Auth 2.0 standard flow across 4 applications. Migrated over 400,000 users in database to OKTA auth server in order to strengthen app security and meet bank compliance standards. Collab with product, design and CS to make the new flow intuitive for existing users.
- empower the CS team by adding RESTful GraphQL endpoints to update client data on the admin application
- help build the custom component library to match Figma designs
- migrate the frontend codebase to use ES6, React-Query, Styled Components and increase test coverage
- write documentation and champion standards for WCAG accessibility
- buddy with new team members to walkthrough codebases, documentation, coding standards and Git practices
- facilitate the RBCx x Hackergal Ambassador Program and Scholarship partnership

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

TouchBistro, March 2019 - April 2020

Typescript, React, Node, Amazon RDS, Jest, Cypress, Datadog

- collaborate with an agile team to add new reporting features to improve customer's business insights and overall UI experience, as well as improve existing performance, data reliability and accessibility
- led the migration of the frontend codebase to a more maintainable and performant codebase

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Tennis Design, September 2018 - October 2019

Vanilla Javascript, jQuery, CSS, HTML, Django Templating

- develop innovative, responsive and accessible websites for education, arts, science, technology and business organizations
- work with designers and a back-end developer to scope, refine and implement invision prototype

MENTOR

Canada Learning Code & Juno School of Technology, April 2018 - March 2022

- engage with students, clarify class material, and mark projects for the Accelerated Web Development and JavaScript Courses at Juno College of Technology
- empower budding developers to feel a sense of belonging and excitement about tech and coding

Education

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PT

Bridge, Oct 2019 - Dec 2019 Advanced program focusing on ES6, React, Redux, Test-Driven development, Git Flow, Agile development and leadership skills.

WEB DEV BOOTCAMP

HackerYou, Apr 2018 - June 20 Intensive program with a focus JavasScript, React, CSS, HTML, Pair Programming and Git skills through hands-on, project-based learning.

B.A. PHILOSOPHY + SOCIOLOGY

University of King's College, Sept 2013 - May 2017 First class honours in Contemporary Studies and Sociology.